Now that we've talked a little bit about
Axios, it's time to pivot again. This
time we're going to start talking about
something that is once again built into
JavaScript. So you don't have to bring
in an external script tag. So this is
just as built in as local storage and
session storage. And that is forms. And
I'm going to show you how to work with
forms. So let's say here I put in my
username and I put in my password and I
hit submit. You'll see here that in the
on click thing I have it logging out
hello world. So, watch here very
closely.
Did you see how it appeared and then
vanished really quickly? What happened?
Well, if you look up at my URL bar, you
can see now it says localhost 5000
username to password pa and it took my
username and put it on the top bar and
my password and put it up there as well.
So, what we did is we actually navigated
to a new page. Um, and that's what
happens when you click a button inside
of a form. And also, typically when that
type of button is type submit, it means
that it wants to submit this form. So
forms are really nice as long as you
include them in form tags because it
bundles up all of the data and submits
it for you. So if I wanted to send all
of this data to a server to a server,
um, this submit button bundles it all up
and sends it somewhere. And we'll keep
talking about that in the next